Barry Peavy

Web & Graphic Designer / Product & UI/UX Designer / Front-End Developer



barry.peavy@gmail.com



+1 678 524 7640



barrypeavy.com



linkedin.com/in/barrypeavy



portfolio

Technical Skills

- HTML/CSS, Responsive UI Design
- Bootstrap, Tailwind
- Figma, Adobe XD, InVision
- Illustrator, Sketch, Photoshop
- Wordpress, Wix, Misc CMS
- Visual Studio Code, Sublime
- MS Office, Google Docs
- JIRA, Pivotal Tracker, Azure DevOps
- Emails, MailChimp, Litmus

Education

BFA — Printmaking

- GitHub, Rails env, Slack, Docker
- Basic WCAG/ARIA/508 Accessibility

Professional Summary

I am a hybrid web UI/graphic and product designer and front-end developer with 15+ years remote experience, well-versed in both creative work (Adobe Creative Suite, Figma) — and more technical work in HTML/CSS and frameworks such as Bootstrap and Tailwind.

Outside of work, my hobbies and interests include playing guitar and banjo, singing, background/commercial acting, nationwide hiking/camping/overlanding, golf, fitness, and DIY projects. I also travel frequently to visit my daughter in Texas, and family on the Georgia coast.

Employment

Web UI and Graphic Designer — Front-End Developer (contractor)

TruChoiceFinancial.com



♠ Apr 2023 — Present

CSS / HTML / Bootstrap / Front-End Developer / Graphic Designer. Responsible for designing, coding, testing, and maintaining the public-facing website, as well as the logged in client portal. Also perform email design/code and marketing graphics.

Web UI Designer - Front-End Developer

FlexJobs / BOLD

Remote

□ Jan 2014 — Present

For 10 years with FlexJobs, I have performed web UI/product design (Adobe CS, Figma, Sketch) and extensive front-end markup (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap) for the entire website, in an Agile dev environment (using Visual Studio, Jira, Rails, Github, Slack).

In this role I work closely with everyone from the CEO, to Project and Product managers, Dev Directors, and Back-End Engineers. I also perform device testing for responsiveness. FlexJobs was acquired by BOLD in early 2023.

Interactive UI Web Designer

Definition6

Atlanta GA

⊕ Mar 2007 — Dec 2007

Took design comps, wireframes, charter documents, and UI layouts and translated into website builds, using semantic HTML and CSS. Performed graphic design work and web page/application design, as well as extensive cross-browser testing. Participated in site-planning and estimate meetings and interacted with various teams.

Web UI Designer — HTML/CSS Developer

Various Contract Roles

Atlanta GA

() Jun 2004 — Dec 2013

Worked on a variety of web/graphic design and development projects for numerous companies — including <u>AutoTrader.com</u>, <u>VeriSign</u>, BellSouth, <u>Dodge Communications</u>, <u>Jackson Healthcare</u>, and <u>Xceleration</u>. These contracts were worked via several IT placement firms — The Creative Group, Matrix Resources, etc.

Studies Abroad Grad Classes

Georgia Southern University

University of Georgia Cortona, Italy

Statesboro Georgia

Google UX Design Professional

Courses in user centered design, UX research, wireframing & prototyping.

Webmaster

Coweta County Schools

Newnan GA

□ Apr 2003 — May 2004

Planned, designed, developed, and tested the main CCSS website. Performed all graphic design work, and built all database-driven web pages and applications.

Developed and managed style specifications for the CCSS website. Tested for cross-browser/OS compatibility and Section 508 standards compliance.

Responsible for the CCSS Employee Intranet, as well as management of 30 individual school websites maintained by school-based technology specialists. Served as the help desk web design resource for these specialists.